state.wv.us 2003-06-21

# Privacy Statement

| 

## West Virginia Privacy Statement

Thank you for visiting the State of West Virginia website. This site has been designed to make it easier and more efficient for West Virginia citizens and businesses to interact with West Virginia State Government. The State of West Virginia is committed to preserving your privacy when you visit our Websites. This privacy statement addresses the collection, security and disclosure of information that may be obtained through the use of websites maintained by the State of West Virginia. 

## Collection of Information

If you visit a website maintained by the State of West Virginia in order to read or download information, we may collect the following information: 

  * The name of your domain; for example, "abzcompany.com"; 
  * The IP address of the client accessing the web site; 
  * The type of browser and operating system used to access our sites; 
  * The Internet address of the website from which you linked directly to our sites, if applicable; 
  * The pages you visit within the State of West Virginia's website(s); and 
  * The links made to other websites through our sites. 

This information is collected for purposes of determining what information is of most and least interest to all visitors and in improving content and performance of the site. This information is not collected for commercial marketing purposes. The State of West Virginia may collect personally identifiable information that you voluntarily provide while visiting a State of West Virginia maintained website. Examples of personally identifiable information may include (but are not limited to): 
  * An e-mail address, if you are communicating with us through e-mail; 
  * Information you voluntarily submit to the State of West Virginia for the purposes of completing or submitting an application or form online; and 
  * Other information volunteered, such as vendor profile/contact information, survey information or content of e-mail. 

In general, please note the information collected, whether or not personally identifiable, is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video and other graphic formats you send us. Information is retained in accordance with existing laws, rules, regulations, and other policies. 

## Public Disclosure

As a general rule, the State of West Virginia does not disclose any personally identifiable information collected online except where permission has been granted, or where the information is public information under the West Virginia Freedom of Information Act W.V.C.A. §§ 29B-1-1 et seq., or other applicable laws. Visitors should be aware that information collected by the State of West Virginia on its websites may be subject to inspection, if such information is a public record or not otherwise protected from disclosure. 

## Link Disclaimer

Websites maintained by the State of West Virginia may contain links to other websites, including those owned or maintained by other government, private, or not-for-profit entities. Such links are provided for convenience and/or information purposes only. A link does not constitute an endorsement of content, viewpoint, policies, products or services of that website. Once you link to a website not maintained by State of West Virginia, you are subject to the terms and conditions of that website, including but not limited to its privacy policy. 

## Trademarks, Service Marks, and Copyrights

All trademarks, service marks or copyrights appearing on this website and other linked websites are trademarks, service marks, or copyrights of their respective owners. Pursuant to 17 U.S.C. Sec. 512(c)(2), notice of claims of copyright infringement should be directed to the Webmaster at [webmaster@gwmail.state.wv.us](mailto:webmaster@gwmail.state.wv.us)

## Information Disclaimer

Information provided on websites maintained by the State of West Virginia is intended to allow the public convenient access to public information. While all attempts are made to provide accurate, current and reliable information, we cannot guarantee that the information will be error-free. Therefore, the State of West Virginia and respective employees, officers and agencies expressly deny any guarantee of the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of any information published through our websites and shall not be held liable for any losses caused by reliance upon the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of such information.   Any person who relies upon such information obtained from these websites, does so at his or her own risk.   The contents of this website are published for information purposes only and subject to change without notice.
